Seamus Heaney papers, 1951-2004
Emory University
- Writings by others, 1964-2004, Series 2; Boxes 65 – 73 and OP9
  - Writings about Seamus Heaney, 1972-2002, Subseries 2.1; Boxes 65 - 67
    - Silverlight, [John?], "Heaney profile," typescript with holograph revisions (Box 67, Folder 28)
    - Simmons, James, "After Eden," poem inscribed for Seamus and Marie, signed and dated Oct. 19 (Box 67, Folder 29)
    - Skarstedt, Sonja A., "The Pen as Spade" poem for Seamus Heaney, typescript 1991 (Box 67, Folder 30)
    - Sleigh, Tom, "Free Bloody Birds," essay on poetry of Frank Bidart, Robert Pinsky and Seamus Heaney, photocopied typescript with holograph note from author to Seamus Heaney (Box 67, Folder 31)
    - Steele, Peter, "The Forty-Five," poem for Seamus Heaney, typescript (Box 67, Folder 32)
    - Sutter, Barton, "The Outhouse," poem for Seamus Heaney, typescript (Box 67, Folder 33)
    - [W?], Danny, pre-publication review of Seamus Heaney's Beowulf: A New Translation, photocopied typescript with note from author (Box 67, Folder 34)
    - Watson, G.W., review of The Redress of Poetry: Oxford Lectures by Seamus Heaney, typescript, 1995 (Box 67, Folder 35)
    - Wright, John, Letter to the Editor [ The New Republic?] regarding review by Seamus Heaney ( The Collected Letters of Dylan Thomas), August 1986 photocopied holograph (Box 67, Folder 36)
  - Other writings, 1964-2004, Subseries 2.2; Boxes 68 - 73; OP9
    - Anonymous, "Article on the Education Summer School for Inclusion in the Magazine of the Royal Society of Literature" [ RSL], typescript (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Anonymous, "Back Home," poem signed Marco, photocopied typescript (Box 68, Folder 2)
    - Anonymous, Collection of poems, photocopied typescript (Box 68, Folder 3)
    - Anonymous, Collection of poems, carbon typescript and photocopied typescript, letter signed Chris, holograph notes, 1969 (Box 68, Folder 4)
    - Anonymous, Discussion of "what Field Day is all about," photocopied typescript with a few holograph corrections (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Anonymous, "Elder," poem with holograph note, signed Patrick, typescript (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - Anonymous, "The Feast of Lughnasa," poem, photocopied typescript (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Anonymous, "Fishermen of Neagh, typescript, 24 pages (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Anonymous, "From the 'Amusement of the Muses,' Book I: The Mimic Muse," collection of poems, photocopied typescript (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Anonymous, "Great Irishmen- Padraic O'Conaire," typescript with clipping and letter, undated (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Anonymous, "Guilty of Dust," poem, typescript, 1984 (Box 68, Folder 11)
    - Anonymous, "Halved," poem for Seamus Heaney, photocopied typescript (Box 68, Folder 12)
    - Anonymous, "Hopkins on Skellig Michael," poetry collection, photocopied typescript (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Anonymous, "Hydriotaphia?" poem, typescript (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Anonymous, "Magician," poem, carbon typescript (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - Anonymous, "Mushrooms," poem, photocopied typescript (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - Anonymous, "Mycenae Wavelengths," poem, typescript (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - Anonymous, "Myths," "No Wind," "Vandal," "Moher Revisited," "Weather and Weatherings," "A Visit on Death, " Bigfoot," typescript with some holograph notes (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - Anonymous, "Nightshift," "Hearth," poems, typescript with corrections (Box 68, Folder 19)
    - Anonymous, "The Provincial Museum Assen," and "Memento Mori," poems, typescript with notations (Box 68, Folder 20)
    - Anonymous, "A Refutation," holograph poem (Box 68, Folder 21)
    - Anonymous, "The Sea in Winter," poem with holograph notes, photocopied typescript (Box 68, Folder 22)
    - Anonymous, "Spirit of the Age," poem, typescript (Box 68, Folder 23)
    - Anonymous, "Swifts," poem, carbon typescript (Box 68, Folder 24)
    - Anonymous, "Teaching German Literature," "Brothers," "An Easy Death," poems, photocopied typescript (Box 68, Folder 25)
    - Anonymous, "A Tie," poem, typescript (Box 68, Folder 26)
    - Anonymous, "Time, Objects, and the Body," essay, typescript (Box 68, Folder 27)
    - Anonymous, "To a Cuckoo at Coolnalough," poem, typescript (Box 68, Folder 28)
    - Anonymous, "Trying on Hats (with a friend), poem typescript (Box 68, Folder 29)
    - Anonymous, untitled poem [for John Hewitt], photocopied typescript, 1977 (Box 68, Folder 30)
    - Anonymous, untitled poem, photocopied typescript (Box 68, Folder 31)
    - Anonymous, untitled poem regarding St. Francis, typescript (Box 68, Folder 32)
    - Anonymous, untitled short story, photocopied typescript with some revisions (Box 68, Folder 33)
    - Anonymous, "Vermeers," poetry collection with note signed Floyd, photocopied typescript (Box 68, Folder 34)
    - Anonymous, "A Visit to Poland: Control, Freedom, and the Appetite for Poetry," essay, photocopied typescript (Box 68, Folder 35)
    - Anonymous, "The Young Islanders," treatment for television documentary, 1996 (Box 68, Folder 36)
    - Awano, Lisa Dickler, The Education of Juan Bobo, Chapter 1: "The First Day of School," novel in progress, typescript with letter from the author, 1993 (Box 68, Folder 37)
    - Bantayehu, Getinet, "Poetry," essay, photocopied typescript (Box 68, Folder 38)
    - Banville, John, excerpt from Kepler: A Novel, typescript with letter from the author dated 14 January 1980 (Box 68, Folder 39)
    - Bazakas, Konstantine C., six poems, carbon typescript, 1978-1981 (Box 68, Folder 40)
    - Bidart, Frank, "Genesis 1-2:4," poem with note signed by the author, photocopied typescript, 1982 (Box 68, Folder 41)
    - Bidart, Frank, "The Sacrifice," poetry collection, photocopied typescript with holograph note signed by the author, 1982 (Box 68, Folder 42)
    - Black, Liam, "Johnny the Goat," poem, typescript, 25 October 1996 (Box 68, Folder 43)
    - Blumenthal, Michael, "Oedipus II," poem, photocopied typescript (Box 68, Folder 44)
    - Booth, Martin, "Four," poem and "Beotham," translation of British epic verse with cover letter from the author, photocopied typescript, 1990 (Box 68, Folder 45)
    - Breen, Robert P., "America's Reef," poem, typescript, signed by the author, 1997 (Box 68, Folder 46)
    - Brodsky, Joseph, rhymed foreword to Peter Viereck's Tide and Continuities: Last and First Poems, May 1993, photocopied typescript (Box 68, Folder 47)
    - Brown, Celia, "Michelangelo," poem, typescript, 1986 (Box 68, Folder 48)
    - Brown, George Mackay, "A Harp for a Wedding," photocopied holograph poem, October 1985 (Box 68, Folder 49)
    - Bryan, Arthur, "Canto II," poem with a few revisions, photocopied typescript (Box 68, Folder 50)
    - Bull, Iris, "Facets of War," "The Gulf," "A Backward Glance," "Without You," "A Walk in Winter," "Gifts," "Cavaliers," "Life's Little Ironies," poems, photocopied typescript, 17 November 19[??] (Box 68, Folder 51)
    - Burns, Gerald, "In her Selected Poems," typescript, 18 July 1988 with "The Myth of Accidence, Book VII" [first half], typescript (Box 68, Folder 52)
    - Buttle, Myra, "Aere Perennius: A Fantasy," typescript, 1964 (Box 68, Folder 53)
    - Campbell, A.R., "Ord Glen," poem, typescript, 1991 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Campbell, Philip, Celtic poem translated into English, holograph manuscript, 1998 (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Crotty, Patrick, review of Ferocious Humanism: An Anthology of Irish Poetry from Before Swift to Years After, W.J. McCormack, editor, facsimile copy, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Dale, Peter, translator "A Selection of Poems of Erminia Passannati," photocopied typescript, 1997 (Box 69, Folder 4)
    - Davie, Donald, "Two Poets," poem, typescript, initialed by the author (Box 69, Folder 5)
    - Dawe, Gerald, "Against Piety: A Reading of John Hewitt's Poetry," essay, photocopied typescript (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Deane, John F., "Seafarer," a version of the Anglo-Saxon poem, photocopied typescript signed by the author with "The Journey," printed Turret Poetry Poem Card No. 17 inscribed and signed by the author (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Deane, Seamus, "The Broken Border," typescript poem (Box 69, Folder 8)
    - Delaney, T.G., "Excavations in Carrickfergus 1974," narrative, photocopied typescript, 1975 (Box 69, Folder 9)
    - DePoor, Donald M., eight poems, holograph and typescript (Box 69, Folder 10)
    - Desmond, John, Introduction of Seamus Heaney [speaker at Walt Whitman Lectures] at Whitman College, 14 February 1999, photocopied typescript with holograph note from the author (Box 69, Folder 11)
    - Donnelly, Brian, "Michael Longley (1939- )," entry for Dictionary of Literary Biography, photocopied typescript, 1983 (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Dowling, Ben, The Calligraphy Shop, poetry collection, photocopied typescript (Box 69, Folder 13)
    - Eder, [?], Untitled collection of poems, photocopied typescript with holograph notes in Seamus Heaney's hand, 1992 (Box 69, Folder 14)
    - Eijkelboom, Jan, "Wegdrijven," translation of poem by Seamus Heaney, photocopied typescript (Box 69, Folder 15)
    - Elman, Richard, translator, "The Old Poet," a map poem of Nicaragua by Mario Cajina Vega, photocopied typescript with note to Seamus Heaney from the author (Box 69, Folder 16)
    - Ewart, Gavin, "To Seamus in Grateful Appreciation of Bed and Breakfast," holograph poem, signed by the author (Box 69, Folder 17)
    - Fitzgerald, Robert, translator, Aeneid II, 3-56, photocopied typescript, 1979 (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - Flanagan, Thomas, Afterword for Ireland's Field Day edited by Seamus Deane, photocopied typescript with holograph corrections (Box 69, Folder 19)
    - Flemming, Alan, Four holograph poems, 1985 (Box 69, Folder 20)
    - Foley, Michael, "Seeing Is Not Believing," holograph poem; "Different Fruit," "Bogey Men," "Saturday Night," typescript with revisions; "Three Poems," published, unknown source (Box 69, Folder 21)
    - Ford, P.K., "Devorgil," poem, photocopied typescript (Box 69, Folder 22)
    - Ford, Walton, Poems with letters from the author, typescript, 1987-1989 (Box 69, Folder 23)
    - Forester, Michael, Souls, Songs and Solitude, poetry collection, photocopied typescript with letter from the author, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 24)
    - French, Elain Warren, The Devlin Brothers," poem holograph manuscript, undated (Box 69, Folder 25)
    - Friel, Brian, Translations, photocopied typescript of play script, ca. late 1970s (Box 69, Folder 26)
    - Gebhardt, Peter, British Bulldog, poetry collection, page proofs, undated (Box 69, Folder 27)
    - Grealy, Lucy, ten poems, photocopied typescript, 1992 (Box 69, Folder 28)
    - Greenblatt, Stephen, "Racial Memory and Literary History," essay, photocopied typescript with holograph note to Seamus Heaney (Box 69, Folder 29)
    - Hammond, David, "The Magic Fiddle," a documentary film proposal submitted by Flying Fox Films, photocopied typescript (Box 69, Folder 30)
    - Hanna, Davoren, "Lines in Time of Mourning," for Seamus and Niall, poem typescript, 1986 (Box 69, Folder 31)
    - Hanson, Matthew Vernon, "William Alfred: A Study in Primary Archival Research and a Prolegomena to a Life of Witnessing," [dissertation], pp1-49 and front matter, 2000 [1of 6] (Box 69, Folder 32)
    - Hanson, Matthew Vernon, "William Alfred: A Study in Primary Archival Research and a Prolegomena to a Life of Witnessing," [dissertation], pp. 50-99 [2 of 6] (Box 69, Folder 33)
    - Hanson, Matthew Vernon, "William Alfred: A Study in Primary Archival Research and a Prolegomena to a Life of Witnessing," [dissertation], pp. 100-149 [3 of 6] (Box 69, Folder 34)
    - Hanson, Matthew Vernon, "William Alfred: A Study in Primary Archival Research and a Prolegomena to a Life of Witnessing," [dissertation], pp. 150-199 [4 of 6] (Box 69, Folder 35)
    - Hanson, Matthew Vernon, "William Alfred: A Study in Primary Archival Research and a Prolegomena to a Life of Witnessing," [dissertation], pp. 200-249 [5 of 6] (Box 69, Folder 36)
    - Hanson, Matthew Vernon, "William Alfred: A Study in Primary Archival Research and a Prolegomena to a Life of Witnessing," [dissertation], pp. 250-275 [6 of 6] (Box 69, Folder 37)
    - Hays, J., "Our Dragon Brings Me Her Love Poem for You," poem, typescript, 1982 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Heaney, Carmel, "Northern Ireland- the Policy of the Government of Ireland," address at Harvard University, photocopied typescript, 1979 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Hewitt, Christopher, poetry collection, photocopied typescript, 1991 (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Hornback, Bert G., "Tables Turned," poem, facsimile typescript, 1997 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Holland, Jack, "Sean Juan: Cantos 1 & 2," photocopied typescript, undated (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Howell, Christopher, Music in the Ice, poems, photocopied typescript, 1973 (Box 70, Folder 6)
    - Hudepol, Hank, Coal Dragon and Other Discoveries, poetry collection, photocopied typescript, 2000 (Box 70, Folder 7)
    - Hughes, Ted, "6 September 1997," poem, typescript [telefacsimile copy], 24 September 1997 (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Hughes, Ted, Birthday Letters, photocopied typescript of poems to include, ca. 1998 (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Hughes, Ted, “The Burnt Fox,” prose, typescript, ca. 1994 (Box 70, Folder 10)
    - Hughes, Ted, holograph notes, undated (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Hughes, Ted, "Walt," poem, typescript, ca. 1989 (Box 70, Folder 12)
    - Hughes, Ted, "A Working Definition of Mythic," in Shakespeare and the Goddess of Complete Being, prose, typescript, ca. 1992 (Box 70, Folder 13)
    - Jennings, Elizabeth, "A Simple Wedding," "Considerations," and "Friendship," with "Crow and the Birds," and Crow's Table Talk," by Ted Hughes; "Beside the Seaside," "Mountain Swim," "Ulster," and A Nativity" by Michael Longley, typescript (Box 70, Folder 14)
    - Johnston, Carol Ann, "Poems My Father Taught Me," photocopied typescript with holograph letter dated 17 December 1989 (Box 70, Folder 15)
    - Kavanagh, Patrick, "The Battle of the Poets," poem, 2 pp., holograph manuscript, signed, dated March 1940 (Box 70, Folder 16)
    - Kearney, Richard, After the Face, poetry collection with holograph letter from the author, photocopied typescript, 1978 (Box 70, Folder 17)
    - Kearney, Richard, "Transitions: Narratives in Modern Irish Culture," essay, photocopied typescript with revisions (Box 70, Folder 18)
    - Keefe, Joan, "An Eighteenth Century Irish Curse: On the Death of Dawson," (from the Irish of Sean Clarach MacDomhnaill), photocopied typescript (Box 70, Folder 19)
    - Keefe, Joan, Translations of Irish Poems, photocopied typescript (Box 70, Folder 20)
    - Kelleher, John V., "Too Small for Stove Wood, Too Big for Kindling: Collected Verse and Translations," photocopied typescript (Box 70, Folder 21)
    - Kendall, Tim, six poems, photocopied typescript (Box 70, Folder 22)
    - Keys, Kerry Shawn, seventeen poems, photocopied typescript, signed, ca. 1998 (Box 70, Folder 23)
    - Kiely Benedict, excerpt from his novel, Nothing Happens in Carmincross, holograph manuscript, 45 pp., ca. 1985 (Box 70, Folder 24)
    - Kobiernicki, Leszek, "The City as a Sea," poem, photocopied typescript (Box 70, Folder 25)
    - Kofman, Gil, "A Turn Away From Home," typescript, 1992 (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - LeMieux, Debbie, "For Yia-Yia (My Grandmother)," four poems, photocopied typescript (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Longley, Michael, poem list for No Continuing City with one poem ("Fanny Hill") from the list, carbon copy, 20 August 1968 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Longley, Michael, Lares, poetry collection, photocopied typescript, 1972 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Longley, Michael, poems dated 1972: "Ghost Town," (1 June 1972), "Curriculum Vitae" (two drafts: 15 April 1972 and 19 April 1972), "Wounds" (undated), "Pateen" (3 November 1972), holograph, some with notes and signed (Box 71, Folder 5)
    - Longley, Michael, poems dated in February 1973: "Death-Watch" (13 February 1973), "A Dedication," "Soft Target," "Sea-Burial," "Genealogy," "The Lodger (20 February 1973), "Arc de Triomphe" (5 March 1973), "The Bat" (20 November 1973 and 23 November 1973), photocopied typescript, signed by the author (Box 71, Folder 6)
    - Longley, Michael, An Exploded View, poem collection, photocopied typescript, 1973 (Box 71, Folder 7)
    - Longley, Michael, poems dated 1974: "The White Goose (1 January 1974), "The Swim" (revised version), "Cross Country," "The Cottage," "Triangle: The Pool, The Lesson," "Fleace," "On Sitting Down…" (5 February 1974), "Belladonna" (13 May and 26 June 1974), "A Birth" (21 June 1974), "Ferry" (15 December 1974), photocopied typescripts, some signed (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Longley, Michael, poems dated 1975: "Aunts: Maude, Daisy," "Master of Ceremonies," "Edward Thomas's War Diary," "Hare," "Tulip," "A Small Hotel" (4 March 1975), " Mole," "A Birth," "The Contributors" (21 March 1975), "Mother-of-Pearl," "The Guelder Rose," "Odyssey," "The Old Story," Loamshire" (8 April 1975), "A Small Hotel" (8 May 1975), photocopied typescripts, some with holograph revisions, some signed by the author (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Longley, Michael, "Home Ground" (May 1978), photocopied typescript, signed and dated (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Longley, Michael, Poems dated 1987: "Love Poem," "Parts of the Body," "Whale," "Runes" (February 1987), photocopied typescript, signed and dated (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - Longley, Michael, poems dated 1990: "Homecoming," "Tree-House" (17 August 1990, signed and dated with holograph note to Seamus Heaney (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - [Longley, Michael?], "Big Derek Walcott," dated 26 April 1993 (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - Longley, Michael, "Poetry," 10 June 1998, typescript with holograph note and date, signed (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - Longley, Michael, undated poems: "Dreams," "The Eel," "Halycon," "Stilts" (for Paul Muldoon), "Pretending to be Drunk," photocopied typescript (Box 71, Folder 15)
    - Longley, Michael, undated poems: "Irish Poetry," "Letters: To Three Irish Poets," "To James Simmons," "To Derek Mahon," "To Seamus Heaney," photocopied typescripts with a small number of holograph corrections (Box 71, Folder 16)
    - Longley, Michael, undated holograph poems: "The Lamplighter," "Home" (Box 71, Folder 17)
    - Longley, Michael, reading sheets for Belfast Poets Group, includes: Narcissus, Dr Johnson Dying, In a Convent Cemetery, Remembrance Day, Gathering Mushrooms, To Bix Beiderbecke, Nausicaa, The Freemartin, sixteen copies (Box 71, Folder 18)
    - Longley, Michael, "The Robin," undated with holograph letter (Box 71, Folder 19)
    - Longley, Michael, poem fragment, holograph (Box 71, Folder 20)
    - M[?], Jeff, "For a Sad Absentee," 21 September 1989, photocopied typescript (Box 71, Folder 21)
    - McCabe, Bernard, "Shop Talk," poem, typescript, signed (Box 71, Folder 22)
    - McCabe, Jane, "Echoes from England: The Poetry of Christopher Reid," essay, photocopied typescript (Box 71, Folder 23)
    - McGuckian, Medbh, "How Precious Also Are Thy Thoughts unto Me," essay, photocopied typescript (Box 71, Folder 24)
    - McGuckian, Medbh, "Photograph of a Passerine in Song," telefacsimile copy, 2000 (Box 71, Folder 25)
    - McGuinness, Frank, "Caolin: A Song for Nice Voices," photocopied typescript (Box 71, Folder 26)
    - McGuinness, Frank, Carthaginians, drama, photocopied typescript, pp. 1-59 [1 of 2] (Box 71, Folder 27)
    - McGuinness, Frank, Carthaginians, drama, photocopied typescript, pp. 60-120 [2 of 2] (Box 71, Folder 28)
    - McGuinness, Frank, adapt. Uncle Vanya by Anton Chekhov, scenes from a rural life in four acts, photocopied typescript (Box 71, Folder 29)
    - MacIntyre, Tom, "The Kathryn Scene," short story, photocopied typescript with letter from the author (Box 71, Folder 30)
    - Maher, Kathleen, "In Media Res," short story, typescript, ca. 2003 (Box 71, Folder 31)
    - Mahon, Derek, "Beyond Howth Head," (For Jeremy Lewis), photocopied typescript signed by the author, March-April 1970 (Box OP9)
    - Mahon, Derek, "A Disused Shed in Co. Wexford," photocopied typescript, signed by the author, 7 November 1972 (Box 71, Folder 32)
    - Martin, Augustine, "Hound Voices Were They All: An Experiment in Yeats Criticism" photocopied typescript with corrections (Box 71, Folder 33)
    - Montague, John, "A Primal Gaeltacht," essay signed by the author, photocopied typescript (Box 71, Folder 34)
    - Montague, John, untitled poem, carbon typescript with holograph note, signed (Box 71, Folder 35)
    - Montague, John, "The Water Carrier," "The Little Flower's Disciple," "Back Door," "Sweeney," "For the Hillmother," "Penal Rock/ Altamuskin," photocopied typescript, undated (Box 71, Folder 36)
    - Morpurgo, Michael, Twist of Gold, photocopied typescript, pp. 1-99 [1 of 2] (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Morpurgo, Michael, Twist of Gold, photocopied typescript, pp. 100-196 and chapter 35 [2 of 2] (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Muldoon, Paul, "Cauliflowers," poem, typescript (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Muldoon, Paul, Mules, photocopied typescript, ca. 1977 (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - Murphy, Richard, "Overboard," typescript poem, undated (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Nagley, Ruth, untitled article regarding formation of Commonwealth Library in Athens, photocopied typescript, 1997 (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - O'Brien, Darcy, Way Down in Little Egypt, photocopied typescript with some revisions, notes, 1989 (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Oldcorn, Tony, "Comparison between The Inferno and Purgatorio and 'The Love Song of J. Alfred Prufrock'" (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Parini, Jay, "Boy, Rising," poem, photocopied typescript with note by the author (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Parker, Michael, "To Grazyna," "Some Time, Years Later" photocopied typescript with holograph letter from the author, 1987 (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Pine, Richard, Diviner: The Mind and Art of Brian Friel, pp. 1-89, photocopied typescript, 1989 [1 of 2] (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Pine, Richard, Diviner: The Mind and Art of Brian Friel, pp. 90-184 and Notes, photocopied typescript, 1989 [2 of 2] (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Pinsky, Robert, "Mr. Mintser," short story, photocopied typescript with some holograph revisions (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Quinn, Gerald, "Joyce and Tenebrae: The Ironic Passion and Death of Gabriel Conroy," 1998; and "Frost's Synecdochic Allusions," 1999, articles for publication, typescript (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Rawling, Tom, "The Barn," poem, typescript, signed and dated by the author, December 1989 (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - Rawling, Tom," The New-born Calf," poem, signed by the poet "for Seamus," typescript, 1982 (Box 72, Folder 16)
    - Reddy, Srikanth, seven poems from Facts for Visitors: Poems, photocopied typescript, 2004 (Box 72, Folder 17)
    - Rodman, Selden, "Greco's Toledo," poem, carbon copy (Box 72, Folder 18)
    - Rifbjerg, Klaus, "Terrains vagues," poem, photocopied transcript, 2001 (Box 72, Folder 19)
    - Sargeant, Howard, "Idol Chatter," "Teenage Equestrienne," and "Double Knife-Throwing Act," poems, typescript (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Savidis, [Anthony?], "George P. Savidis, Greek American Emeritus," Nicholas Christopher lecture, Harvard University, undated (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Scanlan, Patricia, "Bullet in the Gullet," poem, photocopied typescript, 1988 (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Schaller, Edigne, "Catinuity," and two untitled poems, typescript with revisions (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Schoeck, Richard J., ten poems responding to poems of Seamus Heaney, photocopied typescript, with cover letter to Seamus Heaney, 1984 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Schuchard, Ronald, "T.S.Eliot and Ted Hughes," essay, typescript undated (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Sharples, Rachel, five poems, photocopied typescript (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Simmons, James, "Birth," "Rogation Day: Portrush," "Lily," "The Second Time Around," "The Honeymoon," "Knocking On," "Meditation in time of Divorce," photocopied typescript with some revisions (Box 73, Folder 8)